Hello.
In this lecture, we're going to add a camera shake whenever my player character is damaged, just to
add a bit of polish to our game.
So in order to make a camera shake effect instead of Unreal Engine, right Click and Go Blueprint class
and under all classes, search for Shake and you'll select this from one Maintain camera shake and let
us call this our damaged shake.
We want to double click and head inside here.
And we want to be concerned with the details here where we can control the options of our camera shake.
So the oscillation duration basically is how long our camera shake is going to last for.
You can play around with this, but I found a body of 0.25 works well.
I'm going to leave the oscillation blend in time and the oscillation blend out time.
But you can play around with this.
But like the name suggests, it controls how fast it blends in and how fast it blends out.
Next, let's go over to the root oscillation.
This basically controls how far my camera is going to shake into interactions.
So in the pitch, I'm going to show a diagram of the pitch, yaw and roll.
Basically we can play around with those values under both the rot and the lock oscillation.
There are a couple of settings.
The main ones are amplitude and frequency.
The amplitude basically describes how powerful a wave is going to be, and the frequency describes how
frequent the wave is going to be.
So maybe I can have very powerful waves, but I'm only going to have them spawn once.
I'm going to show you that the settings that I worked with, well, you can play around.
So in the pitch, I have an altitude of ten and a frequency of 50.
NPO.
I also have an amplitude of ten and 50.
Then in the lock oscillation, which basically describes how the camera is going to move.
In the Z app, a value of 1000 and had a frequency of one.
So you can play around with all these settings to get like a different camera shake, but that's kind
of the basics of it.
Next, if we close this in order to make this camera shake work, if we go to our EVP.
Whenever my character is damaged, after we damage them, I'm going to strike up here and play world.
Camera shake.
Under fake slept the damaged camera shake that we just made.
And under epicenter.
Just right click and look.
We'll get actor location.
The epicenter basically represents where the camera is going to start shaking from.
And we want it to start shaking from wherever our player character is.
Then we have the inner radius and the outer radius.
Basically anything inside the inner radius will not be affected by the camera shake and anything in
the outer radius will be affected by the camera shake.
The larger this value is, the more the camera is going to shake.
Let's test this out some of the value of 2500 and go compile and go play by Press one.
We can see the camera shakes quite violently.
Maybe that's even a bit too much.
So I'm going to reduce this to something like, let's say 1300 and go compile and play.
So maybe that's a bit.
So I'm just going to try a thousand.
So when I did 1000, it seems to have no effect.
Maybe it's not strong enough.
So I'm going to put 1100.
You could play.
So I think that's a bit better.
If I go back to my camera shake and for example, in the Z, if I made something a bit weaker like 500,
it should not shake up and down as much.
So now I can compile, play and go one.
It's not as much.
And I think that's decent.
So when my pancetta is damaged, we're going to play that little camera shake.